《綠箭俠》前情回顧
Previously on "Arrow"...
西藏蝮蛇毒
Tibetan pit viper venom.
常用劑量對你來說沒用  對吧
A constant dose of that can't be good for you, right?
他會像當初斯萊德那樣昏迷
It'll keep him sedated like it did Slade.
沒提到伊莎貝爾•羅切夫的死嗎
No mention on Isabel Rochev's death?
完全沒有
Not a thing.
-殺我吧  殺我吧  -不  不
- Choose. Choose! - No! No!
不  媽  你幹什麼
No, mom! Mom, what are you doing?
不要殺我的孩子
Both my children will live.
你幹什麼
What are you doing?!
你擁有真正的勇氣
You possess true courage.
不
No!
這件事結束之前  還有一個人
There is still one person who has to die...
必須得死
before this can end.
-不要  -媽
- No... - Mom?!
我莊嚴宣誓
I do solemnly swear
我會支援
that I will support,
維護和遵守星城憲章
defend, and abide by the Starling City charter.
我會忠誠地
And that I will faithfully
接受星城市長
discharge the duties of the office
辦公室的職責
of mayor of Starling City.
我會代表星城居民
That I will tirelessly pursue justice on behalf
不屈不撓地追尋正義
of all of Starling's citizens...
公正無私
impartially,
盡我最大的能力
to the best of my abilities.
願上帝助我
So help me god.
謝謝
Thank you.
西婭
Thea.
我陪著你呢
I'm here for you.
我知道
I know.
奎恩女士
Ms. Queen.
對你的損失  我深表遺憾
I wanted to offer my sincere condolences on your loss.
你媽媽是個好人
Your mother was a good woman.
她會是個很棒的市長
She would have made a wonderful mayor.
謝謝
Thank you.
我想和奧利弗談談
I'd love to speak with Oliver.
如果你看見了他
Well, if you see him,
告訴他  他錯過了自己母親的葬禮
tell him he missed his own mother's funeral.
好幾天都沒人看見奧利弗了
No one's seen Oliver for a few days.
我們應對悲傷的方式各有不同
We all deal with grief in different ways.
失去母親簡直...
And the loss of a parent is...
它能改變你
Well, it changes you.
你意識到你的祖先現在都指望著你
When you realize that your ancestors now look to you;
繼承家族的遺產  延續他們的傳奇
That your family's legacy, their continuing works,
全靠你一個人了
are solely in your hands.
如果你看見奧利弗  告訴他我來過了
If you see Oliver, please tell him that I came by.
當然
Of course.
謝謝
Thanks.
我都不知道我為什麼要哭
I don't even know why I'm crying.
我都不喜歡莫伊拉
I didn't even like Moira.
別人剛死就這樣說她  真是不好
Terrible thing to say about someone after they've just died.
容我辯護一句  她人可不好
In my defense, she was not nice.
她很惡毒
She was diabolical.
這個詞在別人的葬禮上不常聽到
Not a word you often hear at someone's funeral.
你不是為她哭泣  費利西蒂  而是為奧利弗
U're not crying for her, Felicity, you're crying for Oliver.
他在哪兒
Where is he?
他怎麼能不在這裡
How could he not be here?
我不知道
I don't know.
如果奧利弗夠聰明
If Oliver's smart...
就會跑去他的島上躲起來
He ran back to his island to hide.
但也許他會出席你們的葬禮
But maybe he'll attend your funerals.
我一直很喜歡這張照片
I always loved this photograph.
我覺得你媽媽看起來特別漂亮
I thought your mother looked particularly beautiful.
她不覺得
Well, she didn't.
她覺得看起來像是暴眼
She thought she looked bug-eyed.
她沒說過
She never said.
-你現在怎麼樣  -很不好
- How are you holding up? - I'm not.
你媽媽為了你付出了生命  西婭
Your mother gave her life for you, Thea.
她向你展示了有多愛你
She showed you how much she loved you in ways
很少有父母能做到這樣
very few parents ever could.
我知道
I know.
她死的時候都覺得我恨她
She died thinking I hated her.
但我們需要的只是真相
But all we ever needed was the truth.
殺死她的是一個謊言
It was a lie that killed her.
我不明白
I don't understand.
斯萊德•威爾遜
Slade Wilson.
之前他和奧利弗都在那座小島上
He was on that island with Oliver.
出於某種原因  他憎恨奧利弗
And despises him for some reason.
我們的生活中有個精神病
There was a psychopath in our lives
而我哥哥從來沒警告過我們
and my brother never warned us about him.
西婭  你哥哥愛你勝過自己的生命
Thea, your brother loves you more than life itself.
你該留著那張照片
You should keep that photo.
這個潛水艇有六十多年了
This sub is over 60 years old.
戰時這艇擱淺  米拉庫魯就在這艇上
It was carrying the Mirakuru during the war when it ran aground.
有血
Blood.
斯萊德的
Slade's.
他流血過多  即將死去
He was bleeding out, dying.
於是我們決定給他注射米拉庫魯
Until we decided to give him the Mirakuru.
你這主意不怎麼樣
Not one of your better ideas.
我讓你修好潛水艇這個主意怎麼樣
What about my idea for you to fix this sub?
-你當過海軍  -是俄國海軍
- You were in the navy. - The Russian navy.
他們教我們如何擊沉日本潛水艇  而不是駕駛
They taught us how to sink Japanese sub, not pilot them.
阿納托利  拜託
Anatoly, please.
我知道機會渺茫  但如果我們能開動潛水艇
I know it's a long shot, but if we get this sub operational,
我們就能擊敗斯萊德  毀掉米拉庫魯
we can blow Slade and the Mirakuru out of the water
然後離開這座小島
and get the hell off of this island.
除非你有更好的主意
I mean, unless you have a better idea,
這是我們回家的唯一機會
this is our only chance of getting home.
好吧  我盡量
Ok. I try.
星城警察局
襲擊那晚過後  沒人見過斯萊德•威爾遜
No one has seen Slade Wilson since the night of the attack.
他沒有再威脅奎恩家族
I mean, he hasn't made any further threats on the Queen family,
但我們得找到這個王八...
but we got to find this son of a--
先失陪了
Excuse me. Hey.
追悼會沒見到你
Missed you at the reception.
是啊  我得回來
Yeah. I had to get back here,
-看看案子怎麼樣了  -有線索了嗎
- see what was happening with the case. - Any leads?
沒有  威爾遜簡直是個幽靈
No. Wilson's a ghost.
他不是唯一失蹤的人
He's not the only one who's disappeared.
你妹妹有聯繫過你嗎
You heard from your sister?
她只給我發了一條短信  說要換個環境
Nothing apart from a text that she needed a change of scenery.
你還有什麼心事嗎
Something else on your mind?
是塞巴斯蒂安•布拉德
It's Sebastian Blood.
我覺得有點不對勁
There's something that doesn't seem right.
-勞蕾爾  -爸爸  我知道你在想什麼
- Laurel... - Dad, I know what you're thinking.
我指控他殺了他父親的時候  我太急躁
When I accused him of killing his father, I was upset.
但我有過失誤
But just because I had a problem
並不意味著塞巴斯蒂安的事我就錯了
doesn't mean I was wrong about Sebastian.
請你不要糾結這事了好嗎
Please, don't go down this road again, ok?
怎麼又提起這個了
What's bringing this on?
我在追悼會上看到他了
I saw him at the reception.
讓我想到他當選市長的唯一原因是
And it struck me that the only reason that he's mayor now
莫伊拉被殺了
is because Moira was killed.
是的  被斯萊德•威爾遜殺的
Yeah, by Slade Wilson.
如果這之間有聯繫呢
What if there's a connection?
你曾經對我說過
You once told me,
一個員警能做多好取決於直覺
a cop is only as good as his gut.
我是員警的女兒
Well, I'm the daughter of a cop,
我的直覺告訴我
and I know in my gut
塞巴斯蒂安不是你想的那種人
Sebastian is not the man that you think he is.
你確定嗎
You sure?
寶貝  上一次
Baby, last time...
我是個醉鬼  你不相信我是對的
I was a drunk. And you were right not to trust me.
但是  爸爸
But, dad...
我現在需要你的信任
I need you to trust me now.
這項法律只是第一步
This legislation is the first step
讓星城重拾昨日的光芒
toward making Starling City the jewel that it once was.
再次成為一顆明珠
The jewel that it can be again.
有您的電話  布拉德市長
Phone call for you, Mayor Blood.
我還在適應人們這麼叫我  阿莉莎
I'm still getting used to people calling me that, Alyssa.
讓對方留言吧
Please take a message.
對方堅持要與您通話
The caller insisted.
他說他是您父親
He said he's your father.
那不可能
That's impossible.
沒關係
Never mind.
我來接
I'll take it.
喂
Hello?
你好啊  塞巴斯蒂安
Hello, Sebastian.
抱歉打攪你
I'm sorry to bother you.
我就是想打個電話來
I just wanted to check in
問問你第一天上任感覺如何
and see how your first day is going.
很好  謝謝你
Very well, thank you.
不過我現在有點忙
But I'm a little busy right now,
如果不介意的話我過一會兒再打給你
So if you'll allow me to call you back,
我會盡快的
I'll do that as soon as I can.
不需要
No need.
我確信你有很多事情要做
I'm sure you have quite a lot of business to attend to.
畢竟你現在是市長了
You are the mayor now, after all.
所以開始工作吧
So get to work.
我們的蛇毒所剩不多了
We're almost out of snake venom.
羅伊這個樣子讓我想起了巴里
Seeing Roy like this reminds me of Barry.
巴里又讓我想起了尖端科技研究實驗室
And Barry reminds me of S.T.A.R. Labs.
尖端科技研究實驗室讓我想起了
S.T.A.R. Labs reminds me
他們正在研究的米拉庫魯的解藥
of the Mirakuru cure that they're working on,
要是我們現在能用上多好呀
which we could really use...right now.
是啊  特別是因為伊莎貝爾•羅切夫
Yeah, especially since Isabel Rochev
肯定被人注射了那玩意
was clearly injected with the stuff.
你怎麼知道
How do you know?
因為除此之外
'cause there's no other way
她不可能被九毫米中空彈斃命後
she could be walking around after being shot dead-on
還能到處跑
with a nine-millimeter hollow point.
我給奧利弗留了一大堆關於
I've left about a dozen messages for Oliver
伊莎貝爾•羅切夫回歸的語音留言  但毫無回應
about Isabel being back. No response.
你找到他的線索了嗎
You have any luck finding him?
很多  但全是壞消息
Tons. All of it bad.
總之是他的護照  手機
There's been no activity on his passport, cell phone,
銀行帳戶  還有其他東西全都沒有活動
or bank accounts-- what's left of them, anyhow.
星城第一銀行
面部識別也未能在任何機場
And facial recognition hasn't spotted him in any airport,
公交或火車站發現他
bus, or train station.
好吧
Right.
莎拉呢
What about Sara?
一樣毫無蹤跡
Nothing either.
狄格  一般來講人們不會消失得這麼徹底
Dig, people don't just go missing like this,
除非
unless...
別那麼想  費利西蒂
Don't go there, Felicity.
如果她真是那樣了呢
What if she is?
如果奧利弗那樣了呢
What if Oliver is?
也許我們找不到他的原因是
Maybe the reason we can't find him is because--
他還活著  費利西蒂
He's alive, Felicity.
如果他死了  伊莎貝爾•羅切夫肯定
If he wasn't, Isabel Rochev wouldn't be so shy
會毫不遮掩地告訴我們  相信我  他還活著
about rubbing it in our faces. Believe me, he's alive.
我希望你有其他辦法找到他
Well, I hope you have some way on how to find him,
因為我已經竭盡所能了
because I am running out of places to look and people to ask.
我知道該去找誰
I know who to ask.
謝謝你同意見我們
Thanks for agreeing to see us.
狄格爾先生
Mr. Diggle.
我以為上次碰面的時候已經說得很清楚
Thought I made it clear after our last meeting.
超能力聯合調查組不再對你提供幫助了
As far as A.R.G.U.S. is concerned, you're out of favors.
我不是為我自己的事  阿曼達
I'm not asking for myself, Amanda.
我是為星城的每一個人
I'm asking for everyone in Starling City.
我需要你們找到奧利弗•奎恩
I need you to find Oliver Queen.
綠   箭   俠
第二季 第二十一集
狄格
Dig.
那臺計算機用的是XK-15型處理器
That computer's running an XK-15 processor.
費利西蒂
Felicity...
那個東西應該還不存在才對
But that's not even supposed to exist yet.
我想要一個
I want one.
告訴我你找到了什麼
Let me know what you find.
我沒時間找你的朋友  狄格爾先生
I don't have time to keep track of your friends, Mr. Diggle.
我們在處理更緊急的事
We deal with more pressing issues here.
你不明白  奧利弗失蹤了
You don't understand. Oliver's disappeared.
也許他只是需要點時間
Maybe he needs some time.
也許你們兩人
Or is it possible that the two of you
只是沒有找對地方
simply haven't been looking in the right place?
你們試過面部識別了嗎
Did you try facial recognition?
當然了  做過三遍了
Yes, I ran it three times.
阿曼達  拜託了
Amanda, please.
斯萊德•威爾遜有一支
Slade Wilson has an army
強大軍隊個個跟他一樣
of men just like him.
有多少人曾經注射過米拉庫魯
How many men have been exposed to the Mirakuru?
足夠徹底破壞這座城市了
Enough to lay waste to this city.
我們現在就需要找到奧利弗
We need to find Oliver right now.
我會盡力的
I'll see what I can do.
威登酒吧
-莎拉聯繫過你嗎  -沒有
- Have you heard from Sara? - No.
-你能打電話問下曼蒂能不能看店嗎  -好的
- Can you just call Mandy and see if she'll cover our bar?  - Okay.
伊莎貝爾•羅切夫
Isabel Rochev.
我知道你是誰
I know who you are.
我能為你做什麼  羅切夫小姐
What can I do for you, Ms. Rochev?
請節哀順變  西婭
I'm sorry for your loss, Thea.
你來就是為了這個嗎
Is that why you came here?
向我表示哀悼
Offer me your condolences?
對  哀悼  還有這個
My condolences, and to give you this.
是讓你騰出酒吧的通知
It's a notice to vacate the premises.
這個酒吧還有它所位於的鋼鐵廠
This club and the steel factory in which its located
都是奎恩聯合企業的財產
are all assets of Queen Consolidated.
-不  你不能這樣  -事已成定局
- No, you--you can't do this. - It's already done.
我還有多長時間
How long do I have?
兩天
A couple days.
泰森議員想邀請你吃晚飯
Councilman Tyson is asking about dinner.
我今晚有安排了
I already have plans tonight.
不好意思  我不是故意要闖進來的
Hi. Excuse me, I didn't mean to barge in.
只是前臺沒人  所以
It's just that nobody was at your front desk, so...
勞蕾爾  沒事  請進
Laurel, of course, please come in.
你先出去吧
Give us a moment.
兩天裡見到你兩次
Twice in two days.
我怎有如此榮幸
To what do I owe the pleasure?
我倒是希望是有好事
I wish I could say that this was pleasure,
但是有個案子要你幫忙
but it's about a case.
我剛上任  就開始有人找我幫忙了
I've barely moved in and people are already asking me for favors.
我現在真是市長了啊
I guess I really have arrived.
的確如此
You certainly have.
說吧  我能幫你什麼忙
So tell me, how can I help you?
墨菲和鄧利維的案件
Murphy vs. Dunleavy.
政府指控一家房地產開發商
The state's charged a real estate developer
說他們以所謂的"道德問題"為理由
for turning away low-income tenants
拒絕低收入的租客
based on his so-called "Morality."
你坐吧  我猜啊
Have a seat. Let me guess.
我們親愛的公平租賃政策的長官
Our dear fair housing commissioner
不願意出庭當你的專家證人
isn't willing to testify as your expert witness.
沒錯  而且前任市長也不打算對他施壓
Exactly. And your predecessor wasn't willing to lean on him.
那麼你很幸運  因為我跟他不一樣
Well, lucky for you, I'm not my predecessor.
知道嗎  這事讓我想起了以前
You know, this actually reminds me of one I had
我當社區組織者時接的一個案子
during my days as a community organizer.
我正希望如此
I was hoping that it would.
我在創新聯合會見過很多這樣的案件
I've seen dozens of cases like this at CNRI.
我們都記得自己的出身  這是好事
Well, it's a good thing we both remember where we came from.
我很樂意幫你
I'm happy to help.
謝謝
Thank you.
勞蕾爾
Laurel...
你能回地檢辦工作  我真的很高興
I'm really glad you got your job back at the DA's office.
我很期待我們能長久一起共事
I look forward to us working together for a long time.
我也是
As do I.
有用嗎
Is it working?
我們馬上就要遠程訪問那臺電腦了
We're about to remote access the computer right now.
老實說  如果你哪天律師當膩了
I'll tell you this, if you ever get tired of practicing law,
去當間諜一定很成功
you'd make a pretty decent spy.
這事經過批準了對吧
You guys have a warrant for this, right?
你就...
Just...
好極了
Terrific.
至少告訴我這是黑了誰的電腦吧
Could you at least tell me who's computer you bugged?
星城  市長辦公室
你們開什麼玩笑  我還給他投過票呢
You're kidding. I voted for him.
我要知道
I need to know
布拉德有什麼見不得光的檔資料
if there's anything incriminating in Blood's files.
我不管了  反正這工作也沒什麼前途
What the hell, this is a dead end job, anyway.
看上去都沒問題
This all looks pretty benign.
很多政策性檔
Lots of policy papers,
從他競選辦公室轉過來的舊文件
old documents transferred from his campaign office.
新聞發布稿
Draft press releases...
等等  剛才那張
Wait, wait, wait, click back.
立即發布  "發生了這種悲劇
"For immediate release-- my thoughts and prayers
我在此為奎恩家族
are with the Queen family in the aftermath
誠心默哀祈禱"
of this unspeakable tragedy.
他就是在莫伊拉死後寫了新聞發言稿唄
So he worked up a press release after Moira was killed.
不  不是的
No, he didn't.
他是在莫伊拉死前寫好的
He wrote that the day before Moira died.
她說的沒錯  看這個落款的時間
She's right. Look at the timestamp.
2014年4月23日  上午8:16
天哪
Oh, my God.
塞巴斯蒂安早就知道斯萊德會殺她
Sebastian knew Slade was going to kill her.
這是TX50衛星頻率通訊機嗎
Is that the satellite frequency communicator TX50?
我可以摸一下嗎
Can I touch it?
我承認這有點怪有點詭異
I know that sounds a little weird and creepy,
但是我現實生活裡從來沒見過這個
but I've never seen one in real life.
這是機密設備  斯莫克小姐
It's classified equipment, Ms. Smoak.
你一定覺得很有權威
You must feel very powerful...
知道每個人的每件事
knowing everything about everyone.
不是像史達林那種邪惡獨裁者那樣
Not powerful in an evil dictator Stalin way.
更像是"知識就是力量"那樣
More of a... knowledge is power, way.
長官  有情況
Ma'am. We have something.
我早該想到
I should have known.
怎樣
What?
奧利弗在他部署行動的那個藏身處
Oliver's at the lair from which he conducts his operations.
但我們剛從那過來啊
But we were just there.
不是那個地方
Not that lair.
他另一個藏身之所
His other one.
就像騎自行車一樣
Like riding bicycle.
只不過在水下騎
Underwater.
那是什麼聲音
What's that sound?
我們被卡住了
We're stuck.
正如當時的日本人那樣
Like Japanese were.
潛水艇都有魚雷的吧
Submarines have torpedoes, right?
我們能炸開一條路出去嗎
Can we blast our way out?
我現在明白為什麼說你們倆天生一對了
I can see why you two are made for each other.
你喜歡用爆炸解決問題
You like your explosions.
好  魚雷
Yes, torpedoes
我去[俄語]
Chert voz'mi.
你說什麼
What?
這些是回轉魚雷
These are kaiten torpedoes.
是人工作業的
Manually operated.
得有人從裡面控制魚雷
Someone needs to steer from inside.
那控制的人怎麼躲開魚雷的爆炸
Okay, but then, how do they get away from the explosion?
沒法躲開
They do not.
-你們怎麼找到我的  -沃勒說的
- How did you find me? - Waller.
我們都很擔心你
We were worried about you.
你連你媽的葬禮都沒參加
After you missed your mother's funeral.
抱歉我沒有去
I'm sorry that I didn't go.
我當時去墓地了
I left for the cemetery.
可最後卻到這裡了
But I ended up here.
這裡是...
Here is...
這裡是防止鋼鐵廠那邊出問題
Here was a secondary facility
才建造的備用設施
in case the foundry was compromised.
但卻變成了一個我可以...
But it became somewhere that I could just go and...
獨自待著的地方
be alone.
她因我而死
She's dead because of me.
五年前
Five years ago...
我本可以治好斯萊德
I could have cured Slade.
如果那樣  這一切都不會發生
And that would have prevented all of this.
而現在
And now,
剩下這些所有我關心的人
all the people left that I care about,
我們都成了他的獵物
we are all in his crosshairs.
今晚一切都將結束
It ends tonight.
怎麼結束
How?
我把自己交給斯萊德
I turn myself over to Slade.
我要終結這場仇殺
I end this vendetta.
奧利弗  你以為把自己交給他
Oliver, you think this ends
這一切就會結束了嗎
with you turning yourself over to Slade?
是的
Yes, I do.
她死了之後
After she was gone...
他告訴我必須再死一個人
he told me that one more person had to die.
然後就結束了
And then it would end.
斯萊德殺了我就結束了
This ends for Slade when he kills me.
我不接受
I don't accept that.
你也不應該接受
You shouldn't, either.
你不能這麼逆來順受  奧利弗
You can't just accept things, Oliver.
如果我接受了自己的命運
If I had accepted my life,
就會像我母親一樣成為賭城的雞尾酒女郎
I would be a cocktail waitress in Vegas like my mother,
我永遠也不會去上大學
and I never would have gone to college,
永遠也不會跑到千里之外
and I never would have moved a thousand miles away
在奎恩聯合企業工作
to work at Queen Consolidated,
永遠也不會相信一個兜帽瘋子的話
and I never would have believed some crazy guy in a hood
他說我不僅僅能做一個技術女
when he told me I could be more than just some IT girl.
求你了  不要這樣做
Please don't do this.
費利西蒂
Felicity...
有人曾經跟我說過
Someone once told me
英雄主義的本質就是為他人犧牲
that the essence of heroism is to die so others can live.
沒那麼簡單  奧利弗
It's not that simple, Oliver.
就這麼簡單
Yes, it is.
斯萊德的整個計劃
Slade's whole plan
就是要奪走我的一切
was to take everything from me.
他做到了
He did.
他贏了
He wins.
現在只要我死  就都結束了
All that's left is for me to die.
不  一定還有別的方法
No, there has to be another way.
沒有了
There isn't.
西婭  拜託  我明白你很難過
Thea, please. I understand you're upset.
現在我們全都有點情緒化
This is an emotional time for all of us.
我不是鬧情緒
I'm not being emotional.
我...我成了孤兒
I'm...I'm an orphan!
我是個沒有工作沒有家的孤兒
I'm a jobless and homeless orphan.
我在這兒什麼都沒有了
There's nothing left for me here.
我還在這裡
I'm here.
謝謝你  但是
I thank you for that, but...
說實話  我需要重新開始
Honestly, I need to start over.
奧利弗
Oliver.
你沒去參加葬禮
We missed you at the funeral.
也沒參加追悼會
And the reception.
很抱歉我沒有出席
I'm sorry that I couldn't be there.
這裡出什麼事了
What's going on here?
西婭在考慮要離開星城
Thea's thinking of leaving Starling City.
不是在考慮  我決定了
No, I am leaving.
沃爾特  能讓我跟我妹妹聊幾句嗎
Walter, could I speak to my sister for a moment?
我相信你運氣更好
I'm sure you'll have better luck.
奧利  拜託  別想要說服我留下來
Ollie, please. Just don't even try to convince me to stay.
我不會的  我覺得離開是個好主意
I won't. I think it's a good idea.
你應該盡可能遠離星城
You should get as far from Starling City as you possibly can.
我們一家人
In our family,
在你  我  媽媽還有爸爸之間
out of you, me, mom and dad,
你是最好的那個
you are the best of us.
你的心靈最純潔
You have the purest heart.
我不能讓你失去那份純潔
And I can't ever have you lose that.
好嗎
OK?
答應我
You promise me?
好
OK.
我知道自己並非一直都是好哥哥
I know that I haven't always been the best brother,
或是朋友  或是別的什麼你所期望的
or friend, or whatever you've needed me to be.
但是自從你出生以來的每一天
But there has not been a day since you were born
我都因為有你這樣一個妹妹而倍感珍惜
where I didn't cherish having you as a sister.
我...
I'll, um,
等我安頓下來會聯繫你的
get in touch when I get settled somewhere.
呼叫伊莎貝爾
我是奧利弗
It's Oliver.
現在結束一切吧
This ends now.
我會一個人去碼頭
I'll be at the pier, I'll be alone.
我去
I'll do it.
彼得  你會死的
Peter, you'll die.
我已經死了
I'm already dead.
輻射中毒
Radiation poisoning.
艾沃的小禮物
Ivo's little gift.
他說他想知道米拉庫魯是不是能治癒癌症
He said he needed to find out if Mirakuru could cure cancer.
估計我們永遠也不會知道了
Guess we'll never find out.
抱歉  彼得  我不知道
Oh, I'm sorry, Peter, I didn't know.
艾沃說英雄主義的本質就是為他人犧牲
Ivo said the essence of heroism is to die so that others can live.
我一直堅信這一點
I held on to that.
這是唯一能給我希望的事
It's the only thing that gave me hope.
所以我決定去
So I'll go.
也許我無法拯救數百萬的性命
I mean, I may not be saving millions of lives,
但我能救你們
but I'll be saving yours.
這就是一切開始的地方
This is where it all started.
我就在那裡登上了"金牌奎恩"
Got on the "Queen's Gambit" right over there.
我應該死在那艘船上
I should have died on that boat.
如果我死了  這一切都不會發生
If I had, none of this would have happened.
我永遠也不會遇到你
I never would have met you.
莎朵和我母親還會活著
Shado and my mother would still be alive.
其他人也不會因為我而死
No one else is going to die because of me.
狄格爾  搞什麼鬼
Diggle, what the hell?
斯萊德•威爾遜
Slade Wilson.
他把你的身份告訴我了
He told me who you were.
他傷害你了嗎
Did he hurt you?
沒有
No.
他想傷害你
He was trying to hurt you.
你失蹤之後
And when you went missing,
我就聯繫了
I reached out...
你的搭檔們
to your partners.
他們告訴了我你的打算
They told me what you were planning on doing.
我必須那麼做
It's what I have to do.
能讓我們單獨談會兒嗎
Will you give us a moment?
那個計劃實施的那天晚上
You thought about telling me...
你就想告訴我
the night of the undertaking.
幾乎每天晚上我都想告訴你
I thought about telling you almost every night.
那你為什麼不說
Why didn't you?
湯米知道
Tommy knew.
對嗎
Didn't he?
你當時和他在一起
You were with him.
他臨死時你陪著他
You were with him at the end.
他最後的話都是在掛念你
His last words were about you.
他想知道你是否安全
He wanted to know if you were safe.
抱歉我沒能救下他
Sorry I couldn't save him.
還有我母親
And my mother.
但我還能救你
But I can save you.
還能救西婭
And Thea.
只要我今晚了結這一切  我還能救下星城
I can save the city if this ends tonight.
不對
No.
你不能
No!
你不能白白送死  奧利
You can't commit suicide, Ollie.
你不能對我這麼做
You won't do that to me.
還有莎拉  還有你的朋友們
Or to Sara, or to your friends.
還有西婭  奧利弗
Or to Thea. Oliver...
她剛剛失去母親
She just lost her mother.
再失去你就會徹底毀了她
Losing you would destroy her.
但她至少能活著
But she'll be alive.
我對兜帽或者面具或者人造武器
I don't know anything about hoods and masks or human weapons
或這裡的一切並不瞭解
or any of this.
但我瞭解你
But I know you.
我就像熟知自己的名字那樣瞭解你
I know you like I know my own name.
鑒於你的種種秘密  我知道這麼想很瘋狂
And I realize it may sound crazy in light of your secret,
但我對你的為人和品行瞭若指掌  奧利弗
but I know who you are in your bones, Oliver.
而我認識的這個人
And that person--
這個人從不輕言放棄
That person doesn't give up.
這個人總能另辟蹊徑
That person, he always finds a way.
這次不行了
Not this time.
你錯了
You're wrong.
你想保護你深愛的人嗎
You want to protect the people who you love?
那你就必須阻止斯萊德•威爾遜
Then the only way to do that is to stop Slade Wilson.
-勞蕾爾  我做不到  -你當然能
- Laurel, I can't! - Yes, you can!
你需要阻止塞巴斯蒂安•布拉德  因為他
By stopping Sebastian Blood, because Sebastian
正在和斯萊德•威爾遜合謀
is working with Slade Wilson.
我有證據
I have proof.
斯萊德•威爾遜殺死你的母親
Slade Wilson killed your mother
就是為了把塞巴斯蒂安推上市長大位
so that Sebastian could become mayor.
你之前說的他的事全是對的
You were right about him.
戴骷髏面具的人為斯萊德•威爾遜工作
The man in the skull mask works for Slade Wilson.
而一直以來
And this entire time,
這個人就是塞巴斯蒂安
it was Sebastian.
當下的情勢
What's happening
已經遠超你和斯萊德的私怨了
is bigger than you and Slade.
星城需要綠箭俠
This city needs the Arrow.
這是做什麼
What's this for?
我希望你能避一避
I don't want you to be in here.
-不  我要和你在一起  -莎拉
- No, I'm going to stay with you-- - Sara.
如果計劃失敗了
If this doesn't work,
我要確保你的安全
I need you to be safe.
事成之後我們就去找你
We will come for you when it's over.
那好
Ok.
你弄清楚怎麼發射魚雷了嗎
Do you know how the torpedo works?
我爬進去  他發射  我操縱  你祈禱
I get in, he fires, I steer, you pray.
彼得  你的這種行為實在是
Peter, what you're doing is...
看清現實而已
Practical.
我已經壽命將盡
My time's already up.
我想說勇敢
Brave.
你必須知道這點
You need to know that.
我覺得我就沒法像你這樣犧牲自我
And I don't think that I could do something like this.
你已經做到了  看看你為我們做的種種
You have. What you did for us--
殺回船上  救出我們
coming back to that boat, setting us free?
我回到船上是因為我想回家
I came back to the boat because I want to go home.
我本無意拯救任何人
I wasn't thinking about saving anybody.
我  我不是這樣的人
It's...it's not who I am.
或許現在還不是
Maybe not yet.
-發射嗎  -莎拉安全了嗎
- Launch? - Is Sara clear?
-安全了  -那就動手
- Yes. - Yes.
-您好  -幸會
- Hello. - Good to see you.
克林頓  你在車裡等我吧
Clinton. You can wait in the car.
您確定這樣沒問題嗎
Are you sure that's a good idea?
我不會有事的
Nothing's going to happen to me here.
您好啊  市長先生
How are you doing, mr. Mayor?
您好  幸會  很高興見到您
Hi. Good to see you, good to see you.
-您好  謝謝  -謝謝
- Hey, thank you. - Thank you.
-您好  -很榮幸見到您  市長
- Hi. - Good to see you, Sir.
恭喜您  布拉德市長
Congratulations, Mayor Blood.
幸會幸會
Nice to see you.
塞巴斯蒂安  能一起吃頓飯嗎
Sebastian, may I join you for dinner?
麻煩等一下
Hey, can you hold that?
太感謝了  哥們  太感謝了
Oh, thanks a lot, man, appreciate it.
克林頓•霍格
Clinton Hogue.
我有些問題要問你
I have some questions for you.
去死吧你們
Go to hell.
你確定要這麼硬撐著嗎
You sure that's how you want to play it?
你以為我之前沒挨過打嗎
You think I've never took a beating before?
老兄  到最後你會寧可挨打
Pal, you're going to wish I beat you.
我來審問你
I'll be your interrogator.
-逗我呢  -克林頓•霍格
- Is this a joke? - Clinton Hogue.
社會保障號碼為306003894
Social security number 306003894.
你們想幹什麼
What the hell's this supposed to be?
瞧瞧
Oh, look at this.
你在開曼群島還有個銀行帳戶呢
You have a bank account in the Cayman Islands.
兩百萬  小金庫挺充實啊
$2 million, quite the little nest egg.
但是  貌似你剛剛
But...looks like you just
進行了一筆轉賬
approved a wire transfer of
把一百萬電匯進星城的一家慈善機構了
$1 million to a charity here in Starling City.
真是慷慨啊
Very generous.
剩下的該怎麼辦呢
What should I do with the rest?
-綠色和平[環保組織]  -好主意
- Greenpeace. - Great cause!
他們非常感謝你的傾囊相助
And they really appreciate the support.
你個婊子
You bitch!
能上無線網的婊子
Bitch with wifi.
克林頓  看來你父母的
Hey, Clinton, looks like your mom and dad have
退休金投資收益頗豐啊
a really nice retirement portfolio, too,
但是糟了  他們馬上
but they, oh, no, are just
就要做一筆血賠的投資了
about to make some really bad investments.
慢著  別  停下
Ok, wait, just wait--just--stop!
你們想知道什麼
What do you want to know?
我在你母親的追悼會上沒見著你
I missed you at your mother's memorial service.
我本想當面表達哀悼之情的
I wanted to offer my condolences.
你當上市長了
You're the mayor.
恭喜了
Congratulations.
這是你奮鬥多年的夢想
You've always wanted that.
相信我奧利弗  我更希望換種方式上任
Believe me, Oliver, I wish it had happened a different way.
令堂和我  我們政見相差甚遠
Your mother and I, we--we didn't agree on much.
但我們都是為星城著想
But we both wanted what was best for Starling City.
我會幫這座城市重尋希望  我向你保證
I will help this city find its heart again, I promise you that.
你真覺得他...
Do you really think that he...
會讓你這麼做嗎
will let that happen?
斯萊德•威爾遜
Slade Wilson.
你怎麼知道我跟斯萊德•威爾遜的事
How do you know I've been working with Slade Wilson?
因為我就是綠箭俠
Because I'm the Arrow.
怪不得啊
Of course.
現在我都明白了
It all makes sense now.
綠箭俠原來就在我身邊
It was right in front of me.
你到我辦公室跟我握手
You came to my office and you shook my hand.
你說我們一起拯救星城
You said that together, we can save this city.
你覺得你釋放斯萊德的米拉庫魯大軍後
You think that there will be a city to be saved
還有城市可以拯救嗎
after you unleash Slade's Mirakuru army?
他們導致的損失  只是讓星城做好準備
They'll only cause enough damage to make the city ready.
準備接受你的領導嗎
Ready for your leadership?
準備實現我對這個城市的遠大期望
For my vision of what this city could be.
變成更好的城市
A better city.
經歷過暴風雨般的洗禮之後
And after the storm they're about to suffer,
星城人民
the people of Starling
會支持並跟隨我去建造那座城市
will support and follow me to that city.
斯萊德承諾你的絕對不會兌現
Whatever Slade promised you, he will not deliver.
他只是想傷害我
He wants to hurt me.
你只是一盤更大的棋局裡的棋子
You are a pawn in a much larger game.
斯萊德承諾讓我當市長
Slade promised me city hall.
他兌現了這個承諾
And he delivered.
他挺言而有信的
He makes good on his promises.
我知道他也向你作出過承諾
I understand he made you a promise, too.
你想幹什麼
What are you going to do?
你想在大庭廣眾的餐廳裡
You going to stab the mayor
刺殺市長嗎
in a restaurant full of people?
星城的歷史翻開了新篇章  奧利弗
It's a new day in Starling City, Oliver.
無論你做什麼  都無法阻擋歷史的腳步
And there's nothing you can do to stop it.
沃爾特來電
沃爾特來電  拒絕接聽
斯萊德的人今晚要發起進攻
Slade's men are taking the city tonight.
-讓他們試試吧  -人數比我們想像的要多
- They can try. - There's more men than we thought,
都服用了米拉庫魯  可能是場屠殺
all on Mirakuru. It could be a massacre.
除非我們先下手為強
Not if we get to them first.
無論如何  我們按原定計劃行事
We stick to the plan, no matter what.
斯萊德會利用下水道系統
Slade's using the sewer system.
你們可以從洛克街過去  然後往東南走
You can drop in at Rock Avenue and then head southeast.
管線匯集處在沃特街
The lines converge at Water Street.
如果斯萊德的大軍在地下  他可能就在那裡
If Slade's army's underground, that's probably where he'll be.
好  我們走  狄格爾  準備好了嗎
Good. Let's go. Diggle, you ready?
那是當然
Never not.
我也要一起去
I'm coming, too.
不行
No, you're not.
費利西蒂可以把消息給我
Felicity can give me a radio.
我可以時刻告訴你們最新情況
I'll just be your eyes and your ears.
我不會礙事的  我保證
I'll stay out of your way, I promise.
-我不會有事的  -萬一出事了呢
- Nothing will happen to me. - What if it did?
斯萊德的人個個都能力強大  幾乎無法阻止
Slade's men, one on one, they are nearly impossible to stop.
我需要你相信我
I need you to trust me.
我需要你好好的
And I need you to be safe.
那他們兩個呢
But not them?
這件事開始就是我們三個人一起做的
This started with the three of us.
是時候回到最初的陣容了
It's time we got back to that.
今晚我們齊心協力
Tonight we rise up as one
奪回這座城市
and take back this city.
我看到布拉德的大軍了
I have eyes on Blood's army.
收到  我馬上把
Got it. I'm forwarding dig your ping
他們上面街道的設計圖轉發到你手機上
along with the foundation schematics of the topside avenue.
按照我給你畫出的路線走
Follow the route I laid out on the blueprints.
你就會看到結構內部的接合點了
You'll see structural joints in the concrete.
下載中
已完成
都炸掉  布拉德就葬身地下了
Blow them all and Blood gets buried.
明白
Got it.
今天股市以400點開市
The market opened today at 400 points
部分原因是奎恩聯合企業的突然奮起
thanks in part to the surprise rally of Queen's Consolidated.
盡管最近發生了悲劇  但是新領導班子
New leadership has investers excited about
讓投資者對公司的前景大為看好
...the company's future in spite of this recent tragedy.
請問一下  為什麼現在還不能上車
Um, excuse me, why can't I board my train?
抱歉  女士  現在是商務座旅客上車時間
I'm sorry, ma'am, it's just business class right now.
普座稍後就可以了
Coach will be boarding soon.
好吧
OK.
過來  夥計
Come on, pal.
那不是鐵山監獄的逃犯嗎
Isn't that one of the Iron Heights escapees?
這個笨蛋想去搶便利店
Dumbass here tried to rob a convenience store
不過我過去他就束手就擒了
but gave up as soon as I pulled in.
我可以暫時把他留在這裡嗎
Mind if I just stick him here for a minute?
沒問題
No, go ahead.
我跟你說
I'm just asking here.
奧利弗  你一直那麼努力去避免再殺人
Oliver, you've worked really hard not to kill anymore.
把整個街區炸毀埋了那些人無異於謀殺
Dropping an entire block on these guys is murder.
至少是屠殺
Manslaughter, at least.
他們不是人
They're not men.
再也不是了
Not anymore.
狄格爾一準備好就讓他引爆炸藥
Have Diggle blow the charges the moment he's ready.
奧利弗
Oliver?
我們將帶領這座城市走出黑暗
We will lead this city out of the darkness,
你們都將助我一臂之力
and each one of you will help me.
走
Come on.
奧利弗  你到底在哪裡
Oliver, where the hell are you?!
你殺了我...
You killed me...
那就禮尚往來吧
Let me return the favor.
現在幾點了
You got the time?
九點
It's, uh, 9:00.
謝了
Thanks.
奧利弗  快出現
Oliver, please.
星級實驗室來電
西斯科  現在真不是時候
Cisco, now is really not a good time.
那邊
There.
奧利
Ollie!
他們人太多了
There's too many of them!
我們打不過
We can't fight.
我們不跟他們打
We're not going to.
轉舵
Turn the wheel!
往哪個方向
What direction?
無所謂  快轉舵
It does not matter. Just turn the wheel.
-轉不動  -必須轉
- I can't! - That is not an option.
好了
I got it!
天吶  動了
My God. We're moving!
好  太棒了
Good, good.
莎拉  成功了
Sara, we did it.
莎拉
Sara!
奧利弗
Oliver!